There goes the neighborhood.
Monster House is a animation, comedy, family film directed by Gil Kenan.
Monsters under the bed are scary enough, but what happens
when an entire house is out to get you?
Three teens aim to find out when they go up against a decrepit
neighboring home and unlock its frightening secrets.
DJ (voice), played by Mitchel Musso.
Chowder (voice), played by Sam Lerner.
Jenny (voice), played by Spencer Locke.
Nebbercracker (voice), played by Steve Buscemi.
Zee (voice), played by Maggie Gyllenhaal.
Officer Landers (voice), played by Kevin James.
Monster House is a 2006 American animated supernatural horror comedy film directed by Gil Kenan in his directorial debut, from a screenplay
written by Pamela Pettler and the writing team of Dan Harmon and Rob Schrab based on a story written by Harmon and Schrab.
The plot revolves around a neighborhood being terrorized by
a sentient haunted house during Halloween.
The film features the voice talents of Mitchel Musso, Sam Lerner, Spencer Locke, Steve Buscemi, Maggie Gyllenhaal,
Kevin James, Nick Cannon, Jason Lee, Fred Willard, Jon Heder, Catherine O'Hara, and Kathleen Turner.
Produced by Columbia Pictures, Relativity Media, and executive producers Robert Zemeckis' ImageMovers and Steven Spielberg's Amblin Entertainment, the human
characters were animated using motion-capture animation, which was previously utilized in Zemeckis' previous film, The Polar Express (2004).
It was also Sony's first computer-animated film produced by Sony
Pictures Imageworks and Relativity's first animated film.
Monster House was released theatrically by Sony
Pictures Releasing on July 21, 2006.
It received generally positive reviews from critics and grossed
$142 million worldwide against a $75 million budget.
It received nominations for the Academy Award for Best Animated Feature and the Golden Globe
Award for Best Animated Feature Film, but lost to Happy Feet and Cars, respectively.
The film explores themes of mission, monster,
halloween, haunted house, neighbor.
The tone is lighthearted.